Nadira Ali

Mobile Number: 07853847830

Email: Nadiraali188a@gmail.com

PERSONAL PROFILE

A highly motivated, passionate and hard-working teacher, who has excellent interpersonal skills and an enthusiasm for helping children develop and succeed. Achieved great experience leading various children in their educational journeys, regularly demonstrated flexibility and clear communication skills and consistently strives for personal and professional development.

EDUCATION

Birmingham City University PGCE Primary 2016-2017

University of Birmingham

BSc Psychology (2:1)

2011-2014

- Modules include: Child and adolescent clinical psychology, cognition in infants and children, development of attachment behaviour and introduction to mental health and psychological problems
- Dissertation topic: "The Effects of Psychopathic, Conservative, Religious and Vengeful Traits on Intergroup Bias"
- Excellent written communication and critical skills used to shape a persuasive argument in dissertation.

Heath Park Business & Enterprise College, Wolverhampton

2004-2011

- A Levels: Law (A) Psychology (B) English Literature (B) Biology (C)
- 16 GCSEs grades A* C including Maths (A) and English (B)

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Primary Teacher, Lanesfield Primary School

September 2016 – present

- Providing a nurturing classroom and learning environment that helps pupils to love learning and develop as learners.
- Planning and delivering lessons to the highest standard that ensure pupils make progress.

- Working closely with SENCO and learning supports to provide tailored resources and support for pupils with special educational needs.
- Assessing, moderating, monitoring and reporting the progress and attainment of students.
- Helping to establish and maintain discipline across the whole school while providing specilised timetables and behavior management strategies for pupils with behavioural and sensory needs.
- Participating in further training and professional development to become lead teacher for particular subjects and programmes, then disseminating relevant information and training to colleagues including; Maths Mastery training (NCTEM) and Apple Teacher training.
- Mentoring and training teaching students (BEd).
- Organising and leading trips and visits to enhance the learning experience of all pupils.
- Leading after-school enrichment clubs in order to ensure pupils of all backgrounds have the ability to be part of extra-curricular activities.

Learning Support Assistant, Bilston Nursery School

January-July 2015

- One-to-one support work with autistic children, young girl and boy.
- Developed daily programme to facilitate learning, manage problematic behaviour and assist with social development.
- Liaised successfully with a variety of staff including teachers, SENCO, management, therapists and parents.
- Demonstrated resilience while dealing with daily behavioural problems.

Voluntary Teaching Assistant

September - November 2014

- Supported year 6 classes during literacy and numeracy lessons.
- Lead small group sessions targeting academic weaknesses of low achieving pupils.
- Provided on-to-one aid for SEN pupils with their reading.
- Conducted weekly written updates on pupils' performances.

Outreach Mentor, University of Birmingham

March 2013 - June 2013

- Prepared and planned weekly sessions working with year 10 students in underprivileged schools on both an individual basis and in-group contexts.
- Researched mentoring topics specific to the students' needs and sourced resources and activities including sessions on learning styles, time management and revision skills.
- Utilised a flexible approach to ensure that each learner gained the maximum from each session.
- Problem solving skills developed when dealing with challenging and unexpected situations and students.
- Communicated effectively and confidently with a variety of people including learners, teaching staff and senior management.

• Further developed organisation skills through both the planning portion of the job but also in executing sessions in a timely manner.

Research Teaching Assistant, University of Birmingham

March 2012

- Volunteered as a research assistant in a PhD research project analysing educational school-based mental health interventions.
- Supported teachers to deliver lessons on mental health and aided students in completing set tasks/activities on mental health.
- Initiative was vital in teaching uninterested year 8 boys such a complex and stigmatised topic.
- Research was highly praised and published in the 'Biomed Central' journal
- Outstanding outcomes attained from the research including greater understanding of early detection and interventions of mental illness.

TRANSFERBALE SKILLS

- Communication and teamwork Working with a range of people and age groups has enabled the development of clear commination skills, which were demonstrated through leading lessons, staff training and meetings with parents and governors.
- Problem solving Dealing with various challenging and spontaneous circumstances that arise daily from a range of people in a calm and confident manner.
- Interpersonal skills Build strong rapports with pupils, parents and colleagues to provide a learning space that is rich with critical reasoning, innovation and growth.

REFRENCES AVAILABLE UPON REQUEST